# **Daniel Lew**

### **Profile**

I'm a Software Engineer based in Toronto, Canada with experience developing fast, robust cloud applications. I recently built Stagehand, a framework for deploying and managing review apps for frontend applications using Github Actions, AWS infrastructure, and client-side code with Service Workers. I am also comfortable in the Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems.

### Skills

**Backend** Node.js, Express, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful APIs

# Frontend

JavaScript, React/Redux, HTML/CSS, JQuery

## **Tooling**

Git, Linux, Pivotal Tracker

### Cloud

AWS, Digital Ocean, Heroku

# **Professional Experience**

# **Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Stagehand**

2020 - present

### https://stagehand-framework.github.io/ ☑

- Co-created Stagehand, an open-source review apps service for frontend applications
- Prototyped and built Stagehand's infrastructure by stitching together AWS and GitHub Actions
- Utilized GitHub Actions to automatically set up and tear down review apps in response to events
- Designed cloud infrastructure on AWS to host frontend review apps
- Implemented review apps wrapper to provide customizable dashboard using Service Workers and clientside code
- Built an intuitive CLI for the user-interface and collaboration across multiple devices
- Co-authored Stagehand's case study: https://stagehand-framework.github.io/ ☑

## Full-stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

2018 - present

- A Trello-like collaboration board built with Rails and React/Redux
- A multi room chat app over WebSockets built with Node.js/React
- A Request Bin-like tool to receive and inspect request payloads, hosted on a VPS, built with Express JS, MongoDB, and PostgreSQL
- A Rails API to manage projects, users, and auth with JWT, with an RSpec test suite

### **Event Manager, Oliver & Bonacini**

2015 - 2020 | Toronto, Canada

- Managing massive, high-end events such as TIFF, Human Rights Watch, Wedluxe
- Ensuring communications with clients, employees, and other managers are consistent and precise in quick-changing environments

### **Education**

**Launch School** 2018 - 2020

Multi-year full-stack Software Engineering curriculum, mastery-based learning Ruby, JavaScript, SQL, HTTP, HTML, CSS | launchschool.com/employers ☑

Marketing Management, Humber College

2015 – 2016 | Toronto, Canada

Honours Psychology and Sexuality, Marriage, and Family Studies, University of Waterloo

2008 - 2013 | Waterloo, Canada